and you want to order a deep dish while
I wish I was reviewing a pizza I'm
actually talking about rogue's deep dish
weight plates so deep dish plates are
different than your standard weight
plates obviously because of the deep
dish appearance but they're also thicker
which is by Design so quick history
lesson before bumper plates were
invented in the 60s deep dish plates
were actually used during weight lifting
competitions and this is because of that
greater surface area which led to a
decreased chance of the wooden platforms
cracking when the weights were dropped
I've been using these bad boys for a
while and I am pumped to break down my
findings for y'all
what is up everyone it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review ready to go today I've got the
Rogue deep dish plates in for review in
this video I'm going to tell you
everything that you need to know about
these weight plates from the price and
the features of course the pros and the
cons as well as who should or maybe
should not add these to their home gym
but before I get really going today
we've reviewed a lot of weight plates on
barvin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go ahead and search bar
Bend best weight plates and you can find
out for yourself which ones we like the
best
okay so what do I like about these
weight plates well let's talk Aesthetics
I love the way they look I love that
deep dish design right there the
Machining is also super nice I really
don't see any imperfections on here
maybe a little bit on the inside of this
collar just from you know normal wear
and tear meat loading and unloading the
plate onto a barbell the e-coat finished
right here also is going to protect
these weight plates and you know prevent
any corrosion from forming on the plates
so that's really nice as well since
they're thicker than your standard
weight plate they're also going to be
more durable and the chances of them
cracking or breaking when they're
dropped or
really really Slim so that's really nice
something that's got going on here for
them as well and they're made of ductile
iron which is stronger than your
standard gray iron plus they're made in
the good old us of a now obviously love
that and finally there's a lot of buying
options here you can purchase these
individually or as a full set so clearly
there's a lot to like about these weight
plates
[Music]
okay so there's a lot to like about
these plates there's really not too many
issues you might run into but there's
still a few so let's go and get these
out of the way right now space could be
a problem for some of you especially
those power lifters who are you know
getting close to maxing out the weight
on a barbell this might not be the ideal
choice choice for you because they're
thicker than you know any other plate so
that could be a problem for you and Plus
Storage in general could be an issue
because they're going to take up more
space than you really want on your
weight horns and that's just obviously
not a good thing now sticking with that
thickness
it could potentially affect the whip on
your barbell for certain lifts if you
don't know what whip is essentially it's
the amount of bounce that occurs during
the middle of your lift and so these
plates could essentially just change the
overall feel of your exercise and lastly
there's no change plates under 25 pounds
so you'll have to mix and match with you
know some Olympic style plates or really
just whatever you have at home
[Music]
all right so let's dig into the money
now
once again you know you have a lot of
different buying options for you to work
with but let's kick this off with the
individual payers so before shipping 25
pound pair of these deep dish plates is
going to run you right around 120 bucks
the 35s are going to be around 170.
these 45s are about 180 bucks and those
100 pound plates those are going to cost
you around 360 dollars okay so in terms
of sets the 230 pound set is going to
run you around 580 bucks 270 pounds set
it's around 660 320 pounds says around
410 pound set is around a thousand
dollars the 500 pound set is going to
cost you right around 1300 bucks that
570 pound set it's a shade under 1400
and that thousand pound set is going to
run you around 2500 okay so clearly
there's a lot of options for you to
choose from and I love that because that
essentially means there's an option for
everybody out there and these are
actually some of the cheaper plates that
Rogue has to offer so if you want the
Rogue brand you might want to take a
hard look at these but remember you know
they do take up a good amount of space
on your barbell as well as your weight
horns so they might not be worth it for
those Elite power lifters
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features that you'll
find with these weight plates once again
these are made right here in the good
old USA out of ductile iron which is
stronger than your standard gray iron
the machine finish just looks really
good I don't really notice any
imperfections I might need a magnifying
glass to do that the e-coat is going to
add to the corrosion resistance as well
as just overall protect these weight
plates I mentioned all that earlier it's
just worth mentioning it again now as
you can tell by now the appearance on
these 35s and the 45s are different so
this is actually done by Design because
25s and 35s are technically change
plates so they're going to go on top of
the hundreds and the 45s and they're not
really meant to hit the ground so they
don't necessarily need that extra
thickness which is why they don't really
have that deep dish design you know that
this 45 pound plate does so in terms of
thickness that's obviously going to
change as I just mentioned so 25s and
35s share the same thickness they're
right at 1.3 inches thick these 45s are
just under two inches thick and the 100
pound plates are just under three inches
thick now if you compare the thickness
of these plates let's say to an Olympic
style plate from Rogue the 100 pound
plates are nearly an inch thicker 45s
are about 1.5 inches thicker but with
the 25s and 35s there's not that much of
a difference I will say though all
across the board you'll find that the
thickness of these plates are actually
thinner than what you'll find with some
bumper plates and in terms of the collar
openings right here they're right at 50
millimeters which is a shade under two
inches
foreign
so the 230 pound set is going to include
225s and two 45 pound plates the 270
pound set that's gonna include six 45
pound plates the 320 pound set is going
to include 225s let's go along with six
45 pound plate that 410 pound plate is
going to include two of each so 225 35
45 and 100 pound plate that 500 pound
set can actually be customized and
that's going to allow you to really just
pick and choose whichever weight plates
you want as long as it doesn't exceed
500 pounds the 570 pound set is going to
include 425s 6 45s and two hundred pound
plates and lastly that thousand pound
set is also fully customizable so you
can pick and choose whichever ones you
want just remember it can't exceed a
thousand pounds so if you're an advanced
lifter I'd probably suggest going after
that thousand pound set and for the
those intermediate lifters I'd probably
suggest that 410 pound set that way you
do have some variety with your plates
just as long as you're able to spend a
thousand dollars
[Music]
all right so let's go and do a quick
walk around with these plates right here
obviously you know they're deep dish you
can see it right here you have a nice
surface area right here for you to grip
onto it's really helpful when you go to
load and unload your barbell as well as
for storage it is a little bit funky
though because you know it's nice and
flat on the back side right here so it
can be a little bit hard just to
maneuver it sometimes but all in all I
really love the appearance it looks like
a cast iron skillet I mean at least I
could be frying some eggs in here
obviously I'm not going to do that right
now maybe another day if it's hot enough
outside but anyways so there's really
not too many imperfections whatsoever
with this finish maybe a little bit on
the collar on the inside right here just
from normal usage you know but for the
most part I mean these look beautiful in
my opinion now obviously you know this
35 is significantly smaller than the 45
well that's once again by Design because
this is considered a change plate it's
going to go on top of that 45 pound
plate right there so it doesn't need to
be as big or as thick because ideally
you don't want this 35 hitting the
ground so that's why these 45s are
thicker gonna really handle all of that
shock and absorb everything so that this
smaller plate and that 25 pound plate do
not have to do so
[Music]
okay so who should purchase these Rogue
deep dish plates well because of how
durable they are I really think these
could be a great option for anyone to
add to their home gym not only are they
thicker than your standard plate they're
also made of ductile iron and that Eco
is just going to add to the corrosion
resistance since there's a lot of buying
options for you to choose from there's
really an option out there for everybody
plus you can add on more weight
individually as you become stronger and
if you're interested in a weight plate
that is as accurate as possible with you
know what is advertised it's a really
good option for you to consider
foreign okay so what about the people
who might not be too interested in
purchasing these deep dish plates well
let's talk about money yeah I mentioned
earlier these are some of the more
affordable plates that Rogue has to
offer but they can still fall out of
some people's price range so if you are
in fact falling on a budget I'd suggest
looking for a cheaper option out there
the thickness of these plates may not be
ideal for any power lifters out there
because I could essentially just you
know decrease the chance of you really
being able to get to your one rep max
because of how much weight they just
take up on your barbell as well as when
it comes to storage you know they just
are going to dominate a good amount of
space so that could be an issue that you
don't really want to deal with and
sticking with that thickness you know
these could affect the whip on your
barbell and just could mess up your form
and just overall change your overall
experience and how it feels for your
lift
that's about all I got for you today on
the Rogue deep dish plates I love
working out with these bad boys I love
that extra thickness it makes them more
durable and plus they're about as spot
on as it really gets when it comes to
their true weight but you know remember
this might not be ideal for any Elite
power lifters because of how much space
they're gonna take up on your barbell
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was super helpful that I was
able to answer any questions you might
have about these deep dish plates right
here as always stay on the lookout for
my next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
these bad boys right here all you have
to do is search bar Bend Rogue deep dish
plates review our article is going to
pull right up for you and you can read
everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all next time
[Music]
foreign